# **Aaron Parisi**

Web Developer

Building elegant and intuitive UI's often makes me forget to eat - I am a Web Developer based in Seattle, WA, with a passion for the intricacies of asynchronous JavaScript and the creative palette that is React. With my background in Mathematics and experience as a tutor and high school teacher, I hope to bring my drive to help others to the world of frontend development.

Seattle, WA

**518.573.3522** 

https://www.aaronparisi.dev

■ parisi.aaron@gmail.com

in aaron-parisi

aaronparisi

aaron-parisi

#### **EDUCATION**

AppAcademy Full Stack Web Development

(May 2020 - February 2021)

• Object Oriented Design in Ruby

- HTML & CSS
- Database Design & Querying Techniques using MySQL and PostgreSQL
- Data Structures & basic Algorithmic Analysis
- RESTful Application Design & MVC Paradigm in Rails
- Functional & Asynchronous Programming in JavaScript
- Frontend Rendering using React
- Frontend State Management using Redux

Northeastern University

Computer Science Bridge Coursework (January 2016 - May 2016)

- Introduction to Functional Programming
- Data Structures & Discrete Mathematics

Hartwick College
Bachelor's Degree Mathematics,
Economics

(September 2010 -May 2014) 3.9

Discrete Mathematics

- Linear Algebra
- Abstract Algebra
- Real Analysis
- Number Theory
- Econometrics

## SKILLS

Ruby	Rails
JavaScript	React
Redux	SQL
HTML	CSS
Docker	Git
zsh/bash	AWS S3
AJAX	React D3
TypeScript	Pandas

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### RX.DULLC

Web Developer

(May 2022 - Present)

 Freelance frontend development work maintaining and extending several Shoptelligence widgets (TypeScript + React, Polymer)

Plaid, Inc.

(August 2021 - Present)

Technical Support Engineer

- Investigated issues on behalf of Plaid clients, including connectivity failures, data discrepancies, as well as OAuth, MFA, and credentials issues
- Examined Plaid HTTP logs and integrations requests/responses for errors, discrepancies, and behavior patterns
- Executed SQL queries on Plaid database tables to find trends and scope issues
- Reconciled historical transactions data from a variety of JSON sources using Pandas
- Examined Plaid source code to discover, diagnose, and correct bugs
- Promptly communicated Plaid documentation, API behavior, integration errors, and troubleshooting techniques to developers attempting to integrate with Plaid

#### Northeastern University

Computer Science Tutor

• Tutored grad students in Intro to Functional Programming at Northeastern University's Seattle campus

### Salisbury School

Mathematics Teacher

(September 2014 - May 2015)

(September 2017 - December 2017)

• Taught Advanced Placement Calculus BC, Multivariable Calculus, and Probability & Statistics to high school juniors and seniors

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Frontend Sandbox

https://www.frontend-sandbox.aaronparisi.dev/

 Built a landing page for a variety of frontend projects, showcasing animations, games, and adventures learning TypeScript

#### CouponVision

https://www.coupons.aaronparisi.dev

- Generated a large dataset of grocery store product coupon data using data.world's grocery store
  data
- Built a Rails API:
  - Customized database seeding schema, JSON object return data, and API endpoints
- Built several interactive data visualizations using React and D3
  - Line Chart showing number of active coupons over time per grocery store chain
  - Stacked Bar Chart showing distribution of coupon brands among grocery store chains
  - Tile Charts showing total savings available across brands

#### Springfield BnB

https://www.springfield-bnb.aaronparisi.dev

- Built with a React+Redux frontend and a Rails API, this Simpsons-themed Air BnB clone features AWS S3 image storage & frontend authentication
- Configured API to accept CORS requests from both local and live frontends
- Addressed AWS configuration and secret key exposure

## Towers of Hanoi Al Demo

https://www.towers.aaronparisi.dev

- Created an interactive demo version of Towers of Hanoi that relies on ES6 promise syntax and implements the recursive solution to the game
- Designed and implemented intuitive mouseover features using jQuery

## ... and many more!

https://www.aaronparisi.dev